mecr.org 2015-05-01

# Microsoft Privacy Statement

Last Updated: April 2015

Microsoft Research Privacy Statement

Microsoft Technology and Research is one of the largest, most respected computer science research organizations in the world. More than 850 Ph.D. researchers push the boundaries of computing in over 55 areas of study in eleven locations around the globe, and help shape the computing experience of millions of people worldwide through advances that enhance virtually every Microsoft product and service.

This privacy statement applies to the research.microsoft.com website and other Microsoft Research websites or applications that specifically point to the statement.  It does not apply to other online or offline Microsoft sites, applications, products, or services.  Please read the summaries below and click on "Learn More" for more details on a particular topic.

Information We Collect

Summary 

Microsoft collects many kinds of information in order to operate effectively and provide you the best products, services and experiences we can.

We collect information when you register, sign in and use our sites and services. We also may get information from other companies.

We collect this information in a variety of ways, including from web forms, technologies like cookies, web logging and software on your computer or other device. 

Full text 

Microsoft collects many kinds of information in order to operate effectively and provide you the best products, services and experiences we can. Some of this information you provide directly to us. Some of it we get by observing how you interact with our products and services. Some of it is available from other sources that we may combine with the data we collect directly. Regardless of the source, we believe it's important to treat that information with care and to help you maintain your privacy. 

Some  Microsoft Technology and Research applications use application analytics tools to gather data about application performance and the features you use, such as which buttons you press and how often, the quantity of data processed, and how long you use the application. We also collect information about how each application is set up and performing. This data is not stored with any information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you. Typically, application analytics are enabled by default.

What we collect:

  * Registration - When you sign up to use our sites or services you may be required to provide information about yourself, such as your name, birthdate and postal code. 
  * Signing in - To access some Microsoft services, you will need to sign in with an e-mail address and password, which we refer to as your Microsoft account. If you access our services via a mobile phone, you may also be able to use your telephone number and a PIN as an alternative credential to your username and password. By signing in on one Microsoft site or service, you may be automatically signed into other Microsoft sites and services that use Microsoft account. Click here for more Microsoft account privacy information. 
  * Using our sites, applications and services - We collect information that tells us how you interact with our services, including the browser you're using, your IP address, location, cookies or other unique IDs, the pages you visit and features you use, and other analytics. 
  * Data from other sources - We may get additional information about you, such as demographic data we purchase from other companies. 

How we collect:

We use a number of methods and technologies to gather information about how you use our sites, applications, and services, such as:

  * Web forms, such as when you type information into a registration form or type a search query into a search box. 
  * Technologies like cookies and web beacons (Please visit this web page to learn more about these technologies). 
  * Web logging, which enables us to collect the standard information your browser sends to every web site you visit - such as your IP address, browser type and language, and the site you came from - as well as the pages you visit and the links you click while using our sites and services. 
  * Software installed on your computer or other device, which may send back information needed to operate, update or improve that software. 

How We Use Your Personal Information

Summary 

Microsoft uses the information we collect to operate, improve and personalize the products and services we offer.

We also may use the information to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your account and security updates.

And we may use the information to help make the ads you see on our ad-supported services more relevant.

Full text 

Microsoft uses the information we collect to operate, improve and personalize the products and services we offer. Information collected through one Microsoft service may be combined with information collected through other Microsoft services to give you a more consistent and personalized experience in your interactions with us. We may also supplement this with information from other companies. For example, we may use services from other companies to help us derive a general geographic area based on your IP address in order to customize certain services to your geographic area. 

We also may use the information to communicate with you, for example, informing you when a subscription is ending, letting you know when security updates are available or letting you know when you need to take action to keep your account active.

Microsoft provides many of our sites and services free of charge because they are supported by advertising. In order to make these services widely available, the information we collect may be used to help improve the advertisements you see by making them more relevant to you. 

Reasons We Share Your Personal Information

Summary 

Except as described in this privacy statement, we won’t disclose your personal information to a third party without your consent.  We may share anonymized and/or aggregate information with other collaborators for research purposes.

We may also disclose personal information, under circumstances described herein, including with Microsoft affiliates or vendors, when required by law or to respond to legal process; to combat fraud or protect our interest; or to protect lives. 

Full text 

Except as described in this privacy statement, we won’t disclose your personal information to a third party without your consent.  We may share anonymized and/or aggregate information with other collaborators for research purposes.

In addition to any sharing described in the privacy statement for the product or service you are using, Microsoft may share or disclose personal information: 

  * With other Microsoft controlled subsidiaries and affiliates. 
  * As part of a corporate transaction such as a merger or sale of assets. 
  * With vendors and agents of Microsoft.  Specifically we may share with companies we've hired to provide services on our behalf.  When we share information with these other companies to provide services for us, they are not allowed to use it for any other purpose and must keep it confidential. 

We may also access, share, preserve or disclose personal information, including the content of your private content (such as the content of your emails, other private communications or files in private folders) when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary:

  * To comply with the law or legal process or lawful requests including from law enforcement or and government agencies 
  * To protect the rights of Microsoft or our customers, including enforcing the terms governing your use of the services. 
  * To operate an maintain the security of our services, including to prevent or stop an attack on our computer systems or networks. 
  * To protect the personal safety of Microsoft employees, customer or the public. 

Please note that our sites may include links to other sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Microsoft. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by the privacy statements on those sites. We encourage you to review the privacy statement of any site you visit.

Accessing Your Personal Information

Summary 

Some Microsoft services give you the ability to view or edit your personal information online. To help prevent others from viewing your personal information, you first will be required to sign in. How you can access your personal information will depend on which sites or services you have used. 

Full text 

Some Microsoft services give you the ability to view or edit your personal information online. To help prevent others from viewing your personal information, you first will be required to sign in. How you can access your personal information will depend on which sites or services you have used.

 **Microsoft Connect  **  **-** If you are a registered user of Microsoft Connect, you can access and edit your personal information by clicking [Manage Your Connect Profile](https://connect.microsoft.com/profile.aspx) at the Microsoft Connect web site. 

If you cannot access personal data collected by Microsoft sites or services via the links above, these sites and services may provide you with other ways to access to your data. You can contact Microsoft by using the [web form](http://go.microsoft.com/?linkid=4320005). We will respond to requests to access or delete your personal information within 30 days. 

Communication Preferences

Summary 

You can stop the delivery of future promotional email from Microsoft sites and services by following the specific instructions in the email you receive. Depending on the respective service, you may also have the option of proactively making choices about the receipt of promotional email, telephone calls, and postal mail for particular Microsoft sites or services.

Full text 

If you receive promotional email messages from us and would like to stop getting them in the future, you can do so by following the directions in that message.

Depending on the respective service, you may also have the option of proactively making choices about the receipt of promotional email, telephone calls, and postal mail from particular Microsoft sites or services by visiting and signing into the following pages: 

  * Microsoft's [Promotional Communications Manager](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=243191) allows you to update contact information, manage Microsoft-wide contact preferences, opt out of subscriptions, and choose whether to share your contact information with Microsoft partners. If you do not have a Microsoft account, you can manage your Microsoft email communication preferences by using this [web form](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=243189). 

These choices do not apply to the display of online advertising: please refer to the section "Display of Advertising (Opt-out)" for information on this matter. Nor do they apply to the receipt of mandatory service communications that are considered part of certain Microsoft services, which you may receive periodically unless you cancel the service. 

Microsoft account

Summary 

Microsoft account is a service that lets you sign in to Microsoft products, web sites and services, as well as those of select Microsoft partners. When you create a Microsoft account, we ask you to provide certain information. When you sign in to a site or service using your Microsoft account, we collect certain information in order to verify your identity on behalf of the site or service, to protect you from malicious account usage and to protect the efficiency and security of the Microsoft account service.  We also send some of this information to sites and services that you sign in to with your Microsoft account.

We use demographic information – gender, country, age and postal code but not your name or contact information – from your Microsoft account to provide personalized ads to you. **You may opt out of receiving targeted ads from Microsoft Advertising by visiting our** **[ **opt-out page**](https://choice.live.com/AdvertisementChoice/). **

To view additional details about Microsoft account, including how to create and use a Microsoft account, how to edit account information, and how we collect and use information relating to a Microsoft account, please click on Learn More.

Full text 

Microsoft account (formerly known as Windows Live ID and Microsoft Passport) is a service that allows you to sign in to Microsoft products, web sites and services, as well as those of select Microsoft partners.

 **Creating a Microsoft account**

You can create a Microsoft account [here](https://signup.live.com/ "here") by providing an email address, a password and other security information, such as an alternate email address and a phone number. We will use your security information for security purposes only - for instance, to verify your identity or to reset your password if you cannot access your Microsoft account. Some services may require added security, and in those cases, you may be asked to provide additional information. The email address and password that you use to sign up for your Microsoft account are your "credentials" that you will use to authenticate with our network. We assign a unique ID number to your credentials to identify your credentials and associated information. 

You can use an email address provided by Microsoft (such as those ending in outlook.com, live.com, hotmail.com or msn.com) or an email address provided by a third party (such as those ending in gmail.com or yahoo.com) when signing up for your Microsoft account.  You must use an email address that you own on an email service that you have access to. 

When you create a Microsoft account, we will also ask you to provide the following demographic information: gender, country, birthdate and postal code. We may use birthdate to verify that children obtain appropriate consent from a parent or guardian to use a Microsoft account, as required by local law. We use this demographic information for market research.  This demographic information also is used by our online advertising systems to provide you with personalized advertisements about products and services you might find useful, but our advertising systems do not receive or use any information that can personally and directly identify you (such as your name, email address or phone number). If you prefer not to receive personalized ads, you may register your preference with your Microsoft account by visiting our [opt-out page ](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=286759)so that whenever you sign in to web sites or services with your Microsoft account, our advertising systems will not serve you personalized ads. For more information about how Microsoft uses information for advertising, please see the [Microsoft Advertising Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=248689%20). 

Upon creating a Microsoft account using an email address provided by a third party, we will send you an email asking you to verify that you are the owner of the email address associated with your Microsoft account. This is designed to verify the validity of the email address and help prevent email addresses from being used without the permission of their owners. 

We will use the email address you used to create your Microsoft account to send you communications relating to your use of Microsoft products and services and to the security of your account. We may also send you promotional emails about Microsoft products and services as permitted by local law. For information about managing your receipt of promotional communications, please visit [Communications](http://www.microsoft.com/privacystatement/en-us/core/default.aspx?componentid=pspCommunicationModule&View=description). ****

**Signing into software, sites or services with your Microsoft account**

When you sign in to a site or service using your Microsoft account, we collect certain information in order to verify your identity on behalf of the site or service, to protect you from malicious account usage and to protect the efficiency and security of the Microsoft account service. For instance, when you sign in, the Microsoft account service receives your credentials and logs your sign-in name and other information, such as the unique number assigned to your credentials, your IP address, your operating system and web browser version and a time and date. If you use a Microsoft account to sign in to a device or software that is installed on a device, a random unique ID is assigned to the device; this random unique ID will be sent as part of your credentials to the Microsoft account service when you sign in to a site or service with your Microsoft account and will be used to help protect your account. The Microsoft account service sends the following limited verification information to the site or service that you have signed in to: the unique ID number assigned to your credentials that permits the site or service to determine whether you are the same person from one sign-in session to the next; the version number assigned to your account (a new number is assigned each time you change your sign-in information); whether your email address has been confirmed; and whether your account has been deactivated. 

When you sign in to Windows with a Microsoft account, Windows will send standard computer information to Microsoft as well as your device’s manufacturer, model name and version.  We may use this to personalize certain communications to you, such as emails intended to help you get started with your device.  If you sign in to your Windows 8.1 device with your Microsoft account, Windows uses your Microsoft account information to sign you in to Microsoft applications, web sites and services.  To learn more about signing in to Windows with a Microsoft account, please see the [Windows 8.1 Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=280262).

Some third-party sites and services that permit you to sign in with your Microsoft account require your email address in order to provide you with their services. In those cases, when you sign in, Microsoft will provide your email address but not your password to the site or service. If you created your Microsoft account credentials with the site or service, it may have limited access to information associated with your credentials and profile as noted during account creation. 

If you received your account from a third party, like a school, a business, an internet service provider or the administrator of a managed domain, that third party may have rights with respect to your account, including the ability to reset your password, view your account usage or profile information, read or store content in your account, and suspend or cancel your account. In these cases, you are subject to the [Microsoft Services Agreement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=397551 "Microsoft Service Agreement") and to any additional terms of use from that third party. If you are the administrator of a managed domain and have provided your users with Microsoft accounts, you are responsible for all activity that takes place within those accounts. 

Please note that sites and services that permit you to sign in with your Microsoft account can use or share your email address or other personal information that you provide to them as described in their privacy statements. They can share the unique ID number the Microsoft account service provides them only in order to fulfill a service or transaction that you may have requested. All sites or services that use the Microsoft account are required to have a posted privacy statement, but we do not control or monitor the privacy practices of those sites, and their privacy practices will vary. **You should carefully review the privacy statement for each site you sign in to in order to determine how each site or service will use the information it collects.**

 **Connecting your Microsoft account to your social network accounts**

You may connect your Microsoft account to your account on a social network such as Facebook, Twitter or LinkedIn in order to access information from that social network in your Microsoft account.  For example, connecting your Microsoft account to your social network account lets you see status updates or messages from people you have friended or are following on the social network in your Outlook.com inbox; include them in your Microsoft account address book; and view their birthdays in your Microsoft account calendar.  If you choose to connect your Microsoft account to your account on a social network, we will cache certain information about your social network account on our servers so that we can display updated information from your social network account.

You can see a list of the social networks that offer accounts to which you can connect your Microsoft account, as well as the social network accounts that you’ve actually connected to your Microsoft account, by signing in and going to profile.live.com/services. You can disconnect a social network account from your Microsoft account at any time at profile.live.com/services.  If you disconnect a social network account, we will no longer cache information from that account.

Microsoft is not responsible for content originating from non-Microsoft services or for information you share with or send to those services.  If you use a third-party service, its use of your information is subject to its privacy practices. **You should carefully review the privacy statement for each social network account you connect to your Microsoft account to determine how it will use the information it collects.**

 **Accessing your personal information and closing your account**

You can access the personal information in your Microsoft account by going to the Microsoft [account summary page](https://account.live.com/). You can change your username if your Microsoft account does not belong to a managed domain. And you can change your password, alternate email address and phone number. You may also close your Microsoft account by going to [account](https://account.live.com/ "account") and then "Close your account." If your Microsoft account is within a managed domain, there may be a special process for closing your Microsoft account. Please note that if you are an Outlook.com user or have a billing account with Microsoft, if you go to account, you may be redirected to your [account](https://account.live.com/) page for those services.

If you use an email address provided by Microsoft (such as those ending in outlook.com, live.com, hotmail.com or msn.com) when signing up for your Microsoft account, that email address will be unique to you for as long as your Microsoft account is active.  If you or Microsoft close your Microsoft account as provided in the [Microsoft Services Agreement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=397551), that email address or username (but not the Microsoft account itself) may be recycled into our system and assigned to another user.  More information about Microsoft account is available at the [Microsoft account web site](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=397553). 

Cookies & Similar Technologies

Summary 

Most Microsoft websites use "cookies," which are small text files stored on your device, to help operate the sites and collect information about online activity. For instance, we use cookies to store your preferences and settings; help with sign-in; provide targeted ads; combat fraud; and analyze site operations. 

We also use web beacons to help deliver cookies and compile analytics. These may include web beacons from third-party service providers.

You have a variety of tools to control cookies and similar technologies, including:

  * Browser controls to block and delete cookies; 
  * Advertising controls, including Microsoft's controls at <http://choice.live.com/advertisementchoice/>, to opt out of receiving behaviorally targeted ads; and 
  * Controls from some analytics service providers to opt out of data collection through web beacons. 

Full text 

Most Microsoft websites use "cookies," which are small text files stored on your device, to help operate the sites and collect information about online activity.  The text in a cookie often consists of a string of numbers and letters that uniquely identifies your computer, but it may contain other information as well. Here is an example of a unique ID number stored in a cookie that we might place on your device when you visit one of our websites: E3732CA7E319442F97EA48A170C99801.  Our websites may also contain web beacons or other similar technologies.  Microsoft uses cookies and similar technologies for a variety of purposes, described in more detail below. 

**How to Control Cookies and Similar Technologies**

Microsoft provides browser controls to help you manage cookies.  You can also accept cookies but opt out of their use to behaviorally target advertisements.  For instance, Microsoft’s advertising preference and opt-out controls are available at <http://choice.live.com/advertisementchoice/>.

 **Browser Controls to Block Cookies.**

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but allow you to modify your browser setting to block cookies.  For example, in Internet Explorer 11, you can block cookies by taking the following steps: 

  1. Click "Tools" and then select "Internet Options" 
  2. Click the "Privacy" tab at the top of the window 
  3. Move the slider up or down to indicate the rules you want to apply for blocking cookies 

Instructions for blocking cookies in other browsers are available at each browser’s privacy statement.   

Please be aware that if you choose to block cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of Microsoft sites and services that depend on cookies, and any advertising preferences that are dependent on cookies may be lost. 

**Browser Controls to Delete Cookies.**

If you accept cookies, you can delete them later.  For example, in Internet Explorer 11, you can delete cookies by taking the following steps: 

  1. Click "Tools" and then select "Internet Options" 
  2. On the "General" tab, under "Browsing History," click the "Delete" button 
  3. On the pop-up, select the box next to “Cookies” 
  4. Click the "Delete" button 

Instructions for deleting cookies in other browsers are available at each browser’s privacy statement. 

Please be aware that if you choose to delete cookies, any settings and preferences controlled by those cookies, including advertising preferences, will be deleted and will need to be recreated. 

**Browser Controls for “Do Not Track” and Tracking Protection.**

Some newer browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features. Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference to the websites you visit indicating that you do not wish to be tracked. Those sites (or the third-party content on those sites) may continue to engage in activities you might view as tracking even though you have expressed this preference, depending on the sites’ privacy practices. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the DNT signal, Microsoft does not currently respond to the browser DNT signals on its own websites or online services, or on third-party websites or online services where Microsoft provides advertisements, content or is otherwise able to collect information.  We continue to work with the online industry to define a common understanding of how to treat DNT signals. In the meantime, users may continue to opt out of targeted ads from Microsoft as set forth below.

Internet Explorer (versions 9 and up) have a feature called Tracking Protection that helps prevent the websites you go to from automatically sending details about your visit to third-party content providers. When you add a Tracking Protection List, Internet Explorer will block third-party content, including cookies, from any site that is listed as a site to be blocked. By limiting calls to these sites, Internet Explorer will limit the information these third-party sites can collect about you. For more information about Tracking Protection Lists and Do Not Track, please see the [Internet Explorer Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=280122) or [Internet Explorer Help](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=298947). 

**Advertising Opt-Out Controls.**

Because cookies can be used for many purposes, users who do not want to receive behaviorally targeted advertising can choose to accept cookies but opt out from that particular use. Companies in the online advertising industry have developed guidelines and programs to help protect users’ privacy, and these industry programs include web pages you can visit to opt out from receiving behaviorally targeted advertisements from all participating companies (including Microsoft). These pages include: 

  * Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) Consumer Choice Page: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>
  * Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) Opt-Out Page: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>
  * In Europe, you can also visit Your Online Choices: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>

Individual advertising companies may also offer their own opt-out capabilities plus more advanced advertising choices. For instance, Microsoft’s advertising preference and opt-out controls are available at <http://choice.live.com/advertisementchoice/>. Please note that opting out does not mean that you will stop getting ads or see fewer ads; however, if you do opt out, the ads that you receive will no longer be behaviorally targeted. In addition, opting out does not stop information from going to our servers, but it does stop our creation or updating of profiles that might be used for behavioral advertising. 

**Third-Party Analytics Controls.**

As described in more detail below, many websites and online services from Microsoft and other companies use third-party analytic services, which use cookies and web beacons to compile aggregated statistics regarding the effectiveness of promotional campaigns or other website operations.  You can opt out of data collection or use by some of these analytics providers by clicking the following links: 

  * Omniture (Adobe): <http://www.d1.sc.omtrdc.net/optout.html>
  * Nielsen: [http://www.nielsen-online.com/corp.jsp?section=leg_prs&nav=1#Optoutchoices](http://www.nielsen-online.com/corp.jsp?section=leg_prs&nav=1#Optoutchoices)
  * Coremetrics: <http://www.coremetrics.com/company/privacy.php#optout>
  * Visible Measures: <http://corp.visiblemeasures.com/viewer-settings>
  * Google Analytics: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> (requires you to install a browser add-on) 
  * Kissmetrics: <https://www.kissmetrics.com/user-privacy>

**Our Use of Cookies**

Microsoft websites use cookies for several purposes, including: 

  * **Storing your Preferences and Settings.** If you enter your city or postal code to get local news or weather information on a Microsoft site, we may store that city or postal code in a cookie so that you will see the relevant local information when you return to the site. This can save you time by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information every time you visit the site. 
  * **Sign-in and Authentication.** When you sign in to a site or service using your Microsoft account, we store a unique ID number, and the time you signed in, in an encrypted cookie on your device. This cookie allows you to move from page to page at the site without having to sign in again on each page. 
  * **Targeted Advertising.** When we display online advertisements to you, we will place one or more cookies on your device in order to recognize it each time we display an ad to you. Because we serve advertisements on the websites of our advertising and publisher partners, as well as our own, we are able to compile information over time about the types of pages, content and ads you, or others who are using your computer, visited or viewed. This information helps us select the ads we show you.  For example, it helps us try to ensure that you do not see the same advertisements repeatedly. It also helps us select and display targeted advertisements that we believe may be of interest to you. You can find more information about this use of cookies, including how to opt out of receiving targeted advertising from Microsoft, in the [Microsoft Advertising Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=248689). 
  * **Site Analytics.** We may use cookies to count the number of unique visitors to a web page or service or to develop other aggregate statistics about the operations of our sites and services. These analytics help us operate and improve the performance of these sites and services. 

Some of the cookies we commonly use are listed in the following chart. This list is not exhaustive, but it is intended to illustrate the main reasons we typically set cookies. If you visit one of our websites, the site may set some or all of the following cookies: 

Cookie name 

| 

Description   
  
---|---  
  
MUID 

| 

Identifies unique browsers visiting Microsoft sites. It is used for advertising, site analytics and other operational purposes.  
  
ANON 

| 

Contains the ANID, a unique identifier used to help identify which ads a customer may like. It is also used to preserve your choice to opt out of behaviorally targeted ads from Microsoft, if you have chosen to associate the opt-out with your Microsoft account.   
  
CC 

| 

Contains a country code as determined by reverse IP address lookup.  
  
Microsoft account authentication 

| 

Authentication cookies (e.g., RPSTAuth, MSNRPSAuth, KievRPSAuth) used when you sign in with your Microsoft account.   
  
NAP 

| 

Contains an encrypted version of your country, postal code, age, gender, language and occupation, if known, based on your Microsoft account profile.   
  
MH 

| 

Appears on co-branded sites where Microsoft is partnering with an advertiser.  This cookie identifies the advertiser so the right ad is selected.   
  
ACH01 

| 

Maintains information about which ads you clicked on and where you clicked on the ad.   
  
TOptOut 

| 

Records your decision not to receive behaviorally targeted ads delivered by Microsoft.   
  
In addition to the cookies Microsoft may set when you visit our websites, third parties may also set cookies when you visit Microsoft sites. In some cases, that is because we have hired the third party to provide services on our behalf, such as site analytics. In other cases, it is because our web pages contain content or ads from third parties, such as videos, news content or ads delivered by other ad networks. Because your browser connects to those third parties’ web servers to retrieve that content, those third parties are able to set or read their own cookies on your device and may collect information about your online activities across websites or online services. 

**Our Use of Web Beacons**

Microsoft web pages may contain electronic images known as web beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs - that may be used to help deliver cookies on our sites, count users who have visited those pages and deliver co-branded services. Sometimes we include web beacons in our promotional email messages or newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. 

We sometimes work with other companies that advertise on Microsoft sites to place web beacons on their sites or in their advertisements to let us develop statistics on how often clicking on an advertisement on a Microsoft site results in a purchase or other action on the advertiser's site. 

Finally, Microsoft sites may contain web beacons from third parties to help us compile aggregated statistics regarding the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns or other web site operations. These web beacons may allow the third parties to set or read a cookie on your computer. These companies may collect information about your online activities across websites or online servers, however, we prohibit third parties from using web beacons on our sites to collect or access information that directly identifies you (such as your name or email address). You may be able to opt out from data collection or use by these third-party analytics companies as described under “Third-Party Analytics Controls” above. 

**Other Similar Technologies**

In addition to standard cookies and web beacons, websites can use other technologies to store and read data files on your computer. This may be done to maintain your preferences or to improve speed and performance by storing certain files locally. But, like standard cookies, these technologies can also be used to store a unique identifier for your computer, which can then be used to track online activity. These technologies include Local Shared Objects (or "Flash cookies"), HTML5 Local Storage and Silverlight Application Storage. 

Local Shared Objects or "Flash cookies." Websites that use Adobe Flash technologies may use Local Shared Objects or "Flash cookies" to store data on your computer. To manage or block Flash cookies when using Windows, go to the Control Panel and select Flash Player. For other operating systems, learn more at <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>. 

Silverlight Application Storage. Websites or applications that use Microsoft Silverlight technology can store data on your device using Silverlight Application Storage. To learn how to manage or block such storage, visit the [Silverlight Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=117119). 

Children & Parental Consent

Summary 

When a Microsoft site or service collects age information, it will block users under 13 or obtain consent from a parent or guardian before their child can use it. 

When consent is granted, the child's account is treated much like any other account, including being able to communicate with other users.

Parents can change or revoke consent as described in this privacy statement. 

Full text 

When a Microsoft site or service collects age information, it will either block users under 13 or will ask them to provide consent from a parent or guardian before they can use it. We will not knowingly ask children under 13 to provide more information than is necessary to provide the service. 

When consent is granted, the child's account is treated much like any other account. The child may have access to communication services like e-mail, instant messaging and online message boards and may be able to communicate freely with other users of all ages. 

Parents can change or revoke the consent choices previously made, and review, edit or request the deletion of their children's personal information. For example, in their Microsoft account, parents can visit their account, and click on ["Parental Permissions"](https://account.live.com/summarypage.aspx). 

Location Data

Summary 

When you use the location-based services in a Microsoft Technology and Research product or service, Microsoft stores the approximate location of your device along with a unique ID. If you are participating in a user study, the data will be used according to the terms defined by that study. All location information associated with personally identifiable information will be retained no longer than six (6) months, unless otherwise specified with your consent.  Such data will then be anonymized or discarded.

Other Important Privacy Information

Summary 

Learn more about

  * Protecting the security of personal information 
  * Where we store and process information 
  * Changes to our privacy statements 
  * How to contact us 

Full text 

Below you will find additional privacy information you may (or may not) find important. Much of this describes common practices that we want you to know about but don't think it's necessary to highlight in every one of our privacy statements. And some of this is just stating the obvious (for example, we will disclose information when the law requires it), but our lawyers make us say it anyway. Please keep in mind that this information is not a complete description of our practices - this is all _in addition_ to the other, more specific information contained in the privacy statements for each Microsoft product and service you use. 

**On this page:**

  * Protecting the Security of Personal Information 
  * Where Information is Stored and Processed 
  * Changes to Our Privacy Statements 
  * How to Contact Us 

**Protecting the Security of Personal Information**

Microsoft is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems that have limited access and are in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share it. If you are sharing a computer, you should always log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. 

**Where Information is Stored and Processed**

Personal information collected on Microsoft sites and services may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country where Microsoft or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities. Microsoft abides by the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Economic Area, and Switzerland. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. 

Microsoft may retain your personal information for a variety of reasons, such as to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, and as long as necessary to provide services. To learn how to access your personal information, visit Accessing Your Information. 

**Changes to Our Privacy Statements**

We will occasionally update our privacy statements to reflect customer feedback and changes in our services. When we post changes to a statement, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of the statement. If there are material changes to the statement or in how Microsoft will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes before they take effect or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review the privacy statements for the products and services you use to learn how Microsoft is protecting your information. 

**How to Contact Us**

  * If you have privacy questions about a Microsoft Technology and Research Product or Service please email [privmsr@microsoft.com](mailto:privmsr@microsoft.com). 
  * If you have a technical or general support question, please visit <http://support.microsoft.com/> to learn more about Microsoft Support offerings. 
  * If you have a Microsoft account password question, please visit [Microsoft account support](http://windowslivehelp.com/solution.aspx?solutionid=bf5d34bf-db28-44ca-ac9a-93838d81b2d6). 
  * For general Microsoft privacy issues, please contact us by using our [Web form](http://go.microsoft.com/?linkid=4320005). 
  * Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited is our data protection representative for the European Economic Area and Switzerland. The data protection officer of Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited can be reached at the following address: Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited, Attn: Data Protection, Carmenhall Road, Sandyford, Dublin 18, Ireland. 

Microsoft Privacy, Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, Washington 98052 USA

Applications

Summary 

Microsoft Technology and Research publishes applications that assist with behavioral and other research. This module describes the data collection and use practices of Microsoft Research software and services (“Research Applications”) created for Windows 8, Windows Phone, Office, Visual Studio Gallery, Facebook, iOS, and Android.

Full text 

Microsoft Technology and Research publishes applications that assist with behavioral and other research. This module describes the data collection and use practices of Microsoft Research software and services (“Research Applications”) created for Windows 8, Windows Phone, Office, Visual Studio Gallery, Facebook, iOS, and Android.

Research Applications may utilize various capabilities that are provided with your device, including: Location Services, Internet Explorer Mobile, Maps, Microsoft account, People, Pictures & Camera, Search, and Speech..

If a Research Application will use your personal data, you will be prompted to agree to such use.  For information about specific Microsoft features, and your choices for sharing data, please see the appropriate privacy statement: [Office 2013 Privacy Statement](http://www.microsoft.com/privacystatement/en-us/core/otherproducts.aspx), [Windows 8 Privacy Statement](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows-8/windows-8-privacy-statement?ocid=W8_UI), [Windows Phone 8 Privacy Statement](http://www.windowsphone.com/en-US/legal/wp8/windows-phone-privacy-statement). For information specific to 3rd parties, please see the [Facebook Privacy Statement](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/), [Apple Privacy Statement](http://www.apple.com/privacy/), and the [Google Privacy Statement](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).  For information specific to Microsoft HealthVault applications, please see [HealthVault Privacy Statement](https://account.healthvault.com/help.aspx?topicid=privacypolicy), [HealthVault Message Center Privacy Statement](https://apps.healthvault.com/messagecenter/Privacy.aspx) and [HealthVault Connection Center Privacy Statement](https://account.healthvault.com/help.aspx?topicid=HVCCprivacy).

 **Blink** ** ** (updated March 14, 2014)

  * **What This  Application Does:** his application for Windows Phone captures a burst of images to get the perfect shot.  You can return to find a second and third shot from a single capture.  Advanced image stabilization technology from Microsoft Research removes camera shake. You can also share your captures using the Blink.so.cl website, Facebook or Twitter. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:  **This application stores photos to your phone directly. If you wish to share your photo collection, you will need to log in to the selected social media site (Blink.so.cl, Facebook, Twitter) using appropriate credentials. On sharing, your collection will be stored and hosted on Blink.so.cl, but you can choose to make it public (visible to other users) or not (visible only to you). This application uses analytics tools, which are enabled by default, to gather usage and performance data such as screens visited and error occurrences. The data is transmitted to Microsoft in a way that does not identify you or your device. 
  * **Use of Information:**  This application uses collected analytics data to analyze and improve the application. This application does not collect personally identifiable information. 
  * **Choice/Control:** If you choose not to participate in the sharing feature, do not select the option to share on social networks or you can uninstall this application. If you choose not to participate in the collection of analytics data you can uninstall this application. 

**Blink** **  Cliplets **(updated March 14, 2014)

  * **What This  Application Does:** This application for Windows 8 lets you create a "Cliplet" which is a new form of media that combines aspects of a still photograph and aspects of a moving video.  You start by capturing a short video (or open an existing video), then select one frame from the video to serve as the stationary backdrop.  You can then add motion by using touch, mouse or stylus to paint the areas that you want to come to life.  You can share your creations using the Blink.so.cl website, Facebook or Twitter. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:  **This application stores video and Cliplet files on your device.  It also retrieves Cliplets from the Blink.so.cl website to show examples of other people's creations.  If you choose to share your Cliplets, you will need to log in to the selected social media site (Blink.so.cl, Facebook, Twitter) using appropriate credentials.  On sharing, your Cliplets will be stored and hosted on Blink.so.cl, but you can choose to make it public (visible to other users) or not (visible only to you). 
  * **Use of Information:**  This application does not collect personally identifiable information. 
  * **Choice/Control:** If you choose not to participate, do not select the option to share on social networks or you can uninstall this application. 

**Climatology** (updated July 11, 2014)

  * **What This  Application Does:** This mobile application gives the user climate information for anywhere on Earth: temperature, rain, sunniness and frost. Climatology is powered by Microsoft Research's unique FetchClimate technology, originally developed by Microsoft's environmental scientists for climate-related scientific research. Climatology now makes this information easily available to everyone. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed or Transmitted:**   This application does not collect or transmit any personally identifiable data. 
  * **Use of Information:**  This application does not collect personally identifiable information. 
  * **Choice/Control:**   If you choose not to use this application you can uninstall. 

**Eye** **Gaze Keyboard  (**updated February 27, 2015)

  * **What This  Application Does:** This Windows 8 application enables a user to type with their eyes and speak using their computer. The application predicts letters, words and phrases based on context and past typed entries to improve the speed of communication. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed or Transmitted:**   The application collects email address for user identification and contact purposes. Typed entries are collected by default in order to create a customized database for a user. Collected input is stored in a secure database or on the user's device. The application also uses analytics tools, which are enabled by default, to gather usage and performance data such as screens visited, typing rate, and error percent. This information is sent to Microsoft to assist with application support and guidance. 
  * **Use of Information:**  The collected identifiable information will be used to maintain contact with users for guidance and feedback. Typed entries are used to create a customized database for a user, enabling predictive letter, word and phrase selection. Collected analytics are used to analyze usage and to improve the application. 
  * **Choice/Control:**   If you choose not to participate in the collection of typed data, you can click the recording button in the application window to turn off recording. If you choose not to participate in the collection of analytics data, you can uninstall the application. 

**Face Mask, Face Swap, Face Touch** (updated February 24, 2014)

  * ****What These  Applications Do: ****These applications for Windows Phone allow you to modify faces in photos on your Windows Phone.  All photo editing is performed directly on your phone.  No remote service is used.  Edited photos are stored only on your phone. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:** This application stores photos to your phone directly.  It does not store information that personally identifies you and does not send information to Microsoft.  If you want to share your photos you may choose options to login to Facebook, Twitter, Sinsa, Weibo or other third-party websites. 
  * **Use of Information:** The application does not collect personally identifiable information. 
  * **Choice/Control:** If you choose not to participate, do not select the option to share on social networks or you can uninstall the application. 

**Image Composite Editor ****(ICE)  **(updated January 9, 2015)

  * **What This  Software Does: **This application for Windows desktop stitches together photos (or frames from a video) to create panoramic images. You can also use this application to share your panoramic images on the [Photosynth](http://www.photosynth.net/) website. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:  **This application stores photos to your computer directly. If you wish to share your panoramic images, you will need to sign in to the Photosynth site using appropriate credentials. This application uses analytics tools to gather data about how the application is used, how well it performs, and any errors that occur. The data is transmitted to Microsoft in a way that does not identify you or your device. 
  * **Use of Information:  **Microsoft Research uses data collected by this application to analyze patterns of usage and to improve the application. This application does not collect personally identifiable information. 
  * **Choice/Control:  **If you choose to share your panoramic images, you can opt to make them “public” (visible to anyone) or “unlisted” (visible only to those who receive a hyperlink). If you choose not to share your panoramic images, do not sign in to the Photosynth site or do not select the “Publish to Photosynth” option. If you choose not to participate in the collection of analytics data, you can uninstall this application. ****

**InApplication Human Intelligence Tasks (IAHIT)** (updated September 26, 2014)

  * **What This  Software Does:** IAHIT is an in-system reward mechanism. The system enables you to help with research, such as answering survey questions or labeling images. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:** Your responses and other anonymized, aggregated information about you is collected to improve our products and services, and for research purposes. No personally identifying information is collected. 
  * **Use of Information:  **Aggregate information may be shared with research collaborators and third parties. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  If you do not wish to perform a task, you may decline the task. 

**Ink** **Notes** (updated April 16, 2015)

  * **What This  Application Does: **This mobile keyboard allows users to compose handwritten messages and doodles that can be saved and shared with friends. Notes can be sent to a user's contacts stored in their device by email or SMS. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed or Transmitted:  **This application does not collect any information. 

**Jo** **inR** (updated September 26, 2014)

  * **What This  Software Does:** This application for Windows Phone allows you to take an image, or series of images and apply a set of artistic effects. You can also share your edited image/s using the sharing feature of your Windows Phone. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:** This application stores photos to your phone directly. If you wish to share your photo collection, you can use the sharing feature of your Windows Phone. This application uses analytics tools, which are enabled by default, to gather usage and performance data such as screens visited and error occurrences. The data is transmitted to Microsoft in a way that does not identify you or your device. 
  * **Use of Information:  **This application uses collected analytics data to analyze and improve the application. This application does not collect personally identifiable information. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  If you choose not to participate in the sharing feature, do not select the share feature on your Windows Phone. If you choose not to participate in the collection of analytics data, you can uninstall the application. 

**Journeys & Notes** (updated October 15, 2014)

  * **What This  Software Does:** This mobile phone application assigns you a random username an allows you to enter start and end points for a "trip," enter notes about the trip and read notes left by other users that may be relevant to the trip you entered. The application uses the device's location to help identify the closest location based on an entry (e.g. nearest grocery store). 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:** This application collects and transmits GPS (global positioning satellite) signal data to assist in identifying the closest location based on a user entry (e.g., nearest grocery store) and allows users to enter notes or comments on trips that are visible to other users. GPS information is not saved or stored. This application uses analytics tools, which are enabled by default, to gather usage and performance data such as screens visited and error occurrences. The data is transmitted to Microsoft in a way that does not identify you or your device. 
  * **Use of Information:  **This application uses the device GPS location to provide a service. The application uses collected analytics data to analyze and improve the application. This application does not collect personally identifiable information. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  If you choose not to utilize the GPS functionality, you can turn off location services  for the application in your phone's settings. If you choose not to participate in the collection of analytics data, you can uninstall the application. 

**Microsoft  Cloud Offloaded GPS Experimental Kit** ** ** (updated February 24, 2014)

  * **What This  Software Does:** This software collects and transmits GPS signal data, or information about a set of visible satellites derived from GPS signal data. The information is used to provide a service in calculating a location. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:** This software collects and transmits GPS (global positioning satellite) signal data, a reference location, a timestamp and optionally, the true known location to a cloud service that calculates the location from the GPS signal data. 
  * **Use of Information:  **A client ID is generated and collected for the purposes of validating client privilege to use the web service.  A unique request ID is randomly generated in order to send the location calculation back to the appropriate user.  The request ID is not connected to any personally identifiable information. No other identifying information is collected or transmitted. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  If you choose not to participate you can uninstall the software. 

**Microsoft Research Project Doubloon Dash and Project Waterloo** (updated February 24, 2014)

  * **What These  Applications Do:** Project Doubloon Dash and Project Waterloo are Facebook applications that allows you to play simple turn-based game with your Facebook friends. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:** Information about past games, including the Facebook identity of the players and their performance in the game, are used by Microsoft in the game service. Other information available through the Facebook API, such as number of friends, may also be collected. 
  * **Use of Information:**  The information collected is used primarily for providing the Project Doubloon Dash and Project Waterloo game service, as well as for purposes of research in the area of game theory and behavioral economics and other areas. Such research may use information available through the Facebook platform to infer patterns of strategies and behavior in the Project Doubloon Dash and Project Waterloo games.   
The explicit Facebook identifiers of players are removed before storing data inside Microsoft for purposes of research. After all explicit identifiers have been pseudonymized, the aggregate information about game performance may be shared with academic partners for the purposes of research. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  Users have to explicitly grant the necessary privileges to Project Doubloon Dash and Project Waterloo to access their Facebook information. Users can view the data collected in online databases about them in the game's history, and can choose to delete them by deleting the game from Facebook or by visiting the privacy link on the game screen. Data that has been shared and pseudonymized for purposes of research cannot be deleted. 
  * **Important Information:**  Project Doubloon Dash and Project Waterloo games are part of a research project of the Microsoft Research Online Services and Advertising group. More information is available at: <http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/groups/osa/gtmd.aspx>. 

**Photo** **Organizer** (updated February 27, 2015)

  * **What This  Application Does: **This application for Windows phone helps you organizer your photo album by completing small tasks. Each task fine-tunes a photo collection in the app that shows your best photos. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed or Transmitted:   **The application uses analytics tools, which are enabled by default, to gather usage and performance data such as screens visited, and error occurrences. The data is transmitted to Microsoft in a way that does not identify you. 
  * **Use of Information:  ** The application uses collected analytics data to analyze and improve the application. This application does not collect personally identifiable information. 
  * **Choice/Control:   **If you choose not to participate in the collection of analytics data, you can uninstall the application. 

**Q-Play**  (updated February 24, 2014)

 (updated February 24, 2014)

  * **What This  Application Does:** This Windows Phone application allows users to search for activities that other people are doing nearby, or at a particular location. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed or Transmitted:**  The information collected includes location to search for nearby activities, user-supplied search terms, survey responses and device ID.  This application also collects analytics data.  This application does not retain data that is personally identifiable. 
  * **Use of Information:** The information collected is used for research purposes and to improve the application and underlying service that provides the data. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  If you choose not to participate in user surveys, you can exit out of the survey or turn off the option to receive surveys on the About page of the application. If you choose not to send usage data you can uninstall the application. 

**Sketch Match** (updated February 24, 2014)

  * **What This  Application Does**: Sketch Match is an application for Windows Phone that allows you to sketch images and get similarity ratings. You can also search similar images with your sketches. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:**  Sketch Match connects to backend services to find similar images to your sketches, evaluate the similarity of your sketches and the given images, and see ranking in a global leaderboard.  The service queries do not contain any information that personally identifies you. This application also uses analytics tools to gather certain data, which is enabled by default when you use the application, and is sent to Microsoft.  The analytics data does not contain personally identifiable information or information that allows Microsoft to contact you. 
  * **Use of Information:**  The analytics data collected is used to understand user interactions and to improve the Sketch Match experience. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  You can turn off analytics data-gathering by using the Customer Improvement Program control on the application’s Settings screen, or you can uninstall the application. 

**Time of My Life** ** ** (updated February 24, 2014)

  * **What This  Application Does**: This application helps users better understand how their time is spent so they may budget their time better and focus on things that matter most.  The application shows daily, weekly and monthly graphs of where time was spent, with automatically inferred places (such as home, work, gym, restaurant) or activities.  The user may override data inferred by the application or fill in missing pieces where automatic inference does not show them useful data. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:**  This application collects your location, any names that you enter for your locations (such as home, work, etc.), IP address of the device used to access our server, and the type of network used (cellular, Wi-Fi).  The application generates an anonymous password for you and uses it to retrieve your data to generate the graphs when you view your time usage.  Recent data is stored on the device to allow faster graph generation without contacting our servers in the cloud.  We do not collect email, phone number or login credentials. 
  * **Use of Information:**  The location information is used to automatically infer the use of your time such as how much time was spent at home, at work and other places.  The place or activity labels entered by you are used to compute the time spent and generate the graphs shown in the application.  Data collected may also be used to help improve the algorithms used to automatically infer place and activity labels, or to improve other Microsoft products.  We do not use the data collected to attempt to contact you. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  You can disable location data collection in the Settings screen of the application.  Note that disabling location data may cause incorrect data to be shown for time usage and in graphs. 

**Wind** **Up  **(updated June 18, 2014)

  * **What This  Application Does**: This application for Windows Phone allows you to create and share photos, audio clips, text messages or short videos in “Windings” with other WindUp users for a limited period of time. The shared media within a Winding expires after a specified time period or number of views. Windings, and any media within, expire after 36 hours of inactivity, regardless of individual media expiration or view limits. This application requires a Microsoft account. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:**  This application collects information from your Microsoft account including your email address. It also collects the email addresses of any friends you invite to WindUp from your phone’s address book, and the photos, audio, text and videos you upload as your media items. Your Winding and media collection will be stored and hosted on WindUp’s servers, and only visible to those you invite. Expired media and media within Windings that have expired (after 36 hours of inactivity) are deleted from WindUp’s servers. A blurred image representation of expired media may be retained if associated with an active Winding. This application may use analytics tools, which will be enabled by default, to gather usage and performance data such as screens visited and error occurrences. The data is transmitted to Microsoft in a way that does not identify you or your device. 
  * **Use of Information:**  This application uses the personal information collected to personalize your WindUp experience, communicate with you about WindUp services, and to invite friends you select from your phone’s address book. We also use the collected analytics data to analyze and improve the application. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  If you choose not to participate in the sharing feature, you can remove invited WindUp users from your Windings, unsubscribe to Windings you have been invited to view, or  you can uninstall this application. Choosing the “Remove Me” option within the   application will delete your WindUp account and all Windings and media. If you choose not to participate in the collection of analytics data you can uninstall this application. 

**Xim** (updated October 23, 2014)

  * **What This  Application Does**: This mobile application allows users to cast (share) images to other mobile devices they invite to view the content. All devices connected to a cast can see the same set of pictures. Any action, such as swiping or zooming, is visible on all connected devices. Invitations can be sent to the user’s contacts stored in their device by email or SMS. 
  * **Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted:**  This application collects your information (phone number) to create a Xim account and also collects the contact information of friends you select from your phone’s address book. The photos that you cast (share) from your camera roll are temporarily stored hosted on Xim’s servers to enable the cast. The photos and are only visible to those you invite. This application uses analytics tools, which will be enabled by default, to gather usage and performance data such as screens visited and error occurrences. This analytics data is transmitted to Microsoft in a way that does not identify you. 
  * **Use of Information:**  This application uses the personal information collected to personalize your Xim experience, to communicate with you about Xim services and to invite friends you select from your phone’s address book. We also use the collected analytics data to improve the application. 
  * **Choice/Control:**  You can de-authorize your phone number from the settings screen of the application. If you choose not to participate in the collection of analytics data you can uninstall the application.
